Contact

00420739547923 (Mobile) ignacio.garcia.esteban@gmai l.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ignaciogarcía-96a1a22 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Field Operations
Operational Excellence
Communication

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

ITIL v3 Foundation

Prince2 Foundation

SIAM - Service Integration and Management, Foundation

Professional Scrum Product Owner

ITIL 4 Foundation

Honors-Awards

VESPA (Very Special Achievement Award)

VESPA (Very Special Achievement Award)

VESPA (Very Special Achievement Award)

Ignacio García

IT Leader, Ing, MBA Prague, Czechia

Summary

I am an accomplished Service Manager and IT Leader with 20+ years' experience in the delivery of large-scale projects and services. Motivated and results-focused with a proven track record of managing delivery against contracted SLA's and KPI's, in alignment withITIL best practices.

I consistently ensure that services are delivered in line with budget, scope, schedule, risks, outcomes, prioritisation, value and benefits.

A strategic thinker able to excel in challenging environments as well as being a positive communicator with strong analytical skills and a practical approach to solving problems.

Experience

Sysmex Europe Assistant Director ITSM April 2023 - September 2024 (1 year 6 months) Hamburg, Germany

- Manager of Services & Support, reporting to EMEA CIO, responsible for Service Desk and working on the strategy to enhance Service Mgmt. capabilities.
- Product Owner and Project leader of ServiceNow implementation,
 successfully deployed Incident Management in Germany in just 5 months,
 working with SN integrator in an agile set up.
- Incident Manager Process Owner, conducting Service Reviews with the IT Heads to improve Incident Mgmt KPIs and SLAs in continuous improvement

Novartis

Service Excellence - Operations Manager January 2020 - June 2022 (2 years 6 months)

Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

- Appointed as a member of the CoE Leadership Team to drive Service Excellence / Strategic Planning
- Managed Business Operations including Purchase Orders and Invoices for major suppliers (of up to €10 million), licenses compliance, tracking and highlighting deviations from Operations budget, monitoring P&L, Communications and Continuous Improvement.
- Defined CoE strategy and lead DMAIC initiative to improve employee Satisfaction.
- Reported to the senior leadership team on performance against objectives.

Career Sabatical
January 2019 - December 2019 (1 year)

Sabbatical leave to travel and for personal development.

DHL IT Services 12 years 11 months

Principal Service Delivery Manager August 2009 - December 2018 (9 years 5 months) Prague, The Capital, Czech Republic

- Responsible for the provision of Express services in America, mission and business critical ones with a wide range of technologies and Support Models.
- Single point of contact for management escalations of Production related issues.
- Chaired monthly Service Reviews and QBR's
- Managed relationship with suppliers as responsible for multiple contracts with key vendors being signed/renewed on quarterly basis.
- Accountable for negotiating and securing SLAs, along with the KPIs achievement.

Domain Manager (IT Operations)

January 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 8 months)

Prague, Czechia

- Built and led a team of 10 supporting 13 Global services 24x7 and ensured that they had the necessary strategies, training and development plans to consistently achieve in line with business objectives, resulting in improved Knowledge Transfer across the team and resources allocation.
- Introduced a cross functional and cross departmental approach, resulting in an improvement Incident & Problem Management KPI's and customer satisfaction.
- Successfully stabilized critical service and reduce support effort by 30%.

Technical Lead

February 2006 - December 2007 (1 year 11 months)

- Built and led a team of 10 supporting 13 Global services 24x7 and ensured that they had the necessary strategies, training and development plans to consistently achieve in line with business objectives, resulting in improved Knowledge Transfer across the team and resources allocation.
- Introduced a cross functional and cross departmental approach, resulting in an improvement Incident & Problem Management KPI's.
- Successfully stabilized critical service and reduce support effort by 30%.

Capgemini

Senior Consultant

May 2001 - January 2006 (4 years 9 months)

Barcelona Area, Spain

- Working hand in hand with customer since requirements gathering, project development, to post go-live hyper-care.
- Played several roles covering Business Analyst, Technical Analyst, Coding, Testing, Management of small team of developers, Impact and Risk analysis.

Deutsche Bank
CRM Consultant
July 2000 - April 2001 (10 months)
Frankfurt Am Main Area, Germany

 Junior consultant in project to integrate PeopleSoft in Web client for Deutsche Bank Private Banking

Education

University of Pittsburgh - Joseph M. Katz Graduate School of Business

Global Executive MBA, Business Administration and Management, General \cdot (2008 - 2009)

Universidad de Zaragoza

Computer Engineer · (1992 - 1999)